<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Scrolling Text</string>
    <string name="article_title">Monterey Pop 1967 Songs</string>
    <string name="article_subtitle">A collection of songs from the time of Monterey Pop in 1967</string>
    <string name="article_text">The Monterey International Pop Festival, June 16-18, 1967, was the melting pot that merged rock ‘n’ roll, pop, psychedelic music, folk, and elements of rhythm and blues, country blues, country/western, jazz, and even world music, into what we now call rock.

\n\n
        Monterey Pop, the film by D.A. Pennebaker, is one of the 10 best rockumentaries of all time and a pivotal moment in the history of rock music. It is available on DVD as The Complete Monterey Pop Festival-Criterion Collection, which includes the film by D.A. Pennebaker, outtakes, and other selections. Watching it a few years after it came out, some time in the early 1970s, the film steered me right back into examining the origins of rock music. “You know, I’ve heard some of these bands,” says a fan in the beginning of the film, “but to here all of these bands at the same time, that’s gonna be too much…”
\n\n
“And so the Monterey Pop Festival became the first powwow of the Love Crowd, the perfect pastorale, chocked with music and warmhearted people. Its success was so unprecedented that it took everyone by surprise. You see, at the beginning nobody was sure that the Love Crowd was out there.” — Robert Christgau, Esquire, Jan. 1968.
    Scenes from Monterey Pop
\n\n
        The film shows the flower children arriving and partying with a free abandon that presaged Woodstock by two years. The day-glo painted Prankster bus was there. Who can forget the young fan with the American flag painted on his bald head? Michelle Phillips of the Mamas and Papas holding on the phone for Dionne Warwick. Monterey’s finest in law enforcement, wearing riot helmets, smiling and milling about with nothing to do. Mama Cass Eliot in the front row gasping with astonishment over Janis Joplin’s performance. Mickey Dolenz of the Monkees leading the cheer for Ravi Shankar, after Mike Bloomfield knelt in rapt attention at his feet. White suburban kids in sunglasses and flower print dresses and bleached blonde hair, grooving to the earthy blues of Canned Heat and Paul Butterfield.
 \n\n
        Many legends of rock held their debut performances there, in front of an international audience, including Janis Joplin (who had not been heard outside San Francisco), the Who and Jimi Hendrix (who had been heard only in England at that time), and the San Francisco psychedelic pioneers (Jefferson Airplane, Grateful Dead, Big Brother and the Holding Company, Country Joe and the Fish, even Moby Grape). The festival also featured artists that were already popular, from the Swinging London-based Animals to the Los Angeles-based Byrds, and icons of the pop music world including Simon and Garfunkel, the Mamas and the Papas, and Otis Redding. Brian Jones of the Rolling Stones was on hand to be MC. All of pop royalty were involved, including the Beatles, which donated equipment. In fact, Paul McCartney, as a board member of the concert, had recommended the Jimi Hendrix Experience.


    </string>
</resources>